

Vancouver, Canada

+1-604-418-1985 • alecng94@gmail.com alecng.ca • linkedin.com/in/alecng • github.com/alec-ng

Professional Summary

Software engineer with 3.5 years industry experience in web app development, technical architecture, and business consulting. Delivered multiple web portal applications used by over 50,000 users as a tech lead responsible for the design, implementation, and release. Expertise lies in combining a technical foundation in full stack engineering with strong client services and interpersonal skills.

Skills

Front-End: React, ES6 JavaScript, Node.js, Jest, Enzyme, HTML5, CSS3, Salesforce Aura Components, Lightning Web Components (LWC), Bootstrap, Webpack

Back-End: NoSQL, Relational Database Design, SQL, Salesforce Apex Object Oriented Programming (OOP) Language, Salesforce Object Query Language (SOQL), Google Firebase

Software Processes: Git, Continuous Integration (CI), Continuous Deployment (CD), Test Driven Development (TDD), Behaviour Driven Development (BDD), Agile Methodology, Open Source

Client Service: Product Demos, Business Presentations, Requirement Gathering, Training Sessions, Cross-team collaboration

Work Experience

Groundswell Cloud Solutions

Senior Technical Consultant

Jan 2019 - Oct 2019

- Managed a team of 6 as a tech lead in the implementation and release of a mobile app feature deployed to over 13,000 users by reviewing code, delegating tasks, and handling deployments
- Led client facing software architecture engagements on security, scalability and data migration strategies for a customer portal to be rolled out to 600,000 users across 3 continents
- Formalized and documented the company's security guidelines for Salesforce development based on OWASP and Salesforce standards
- Developed excellent communication and time management skills from working with a partially distributed team alongside clients in different time zones

Technical Consultant Sep 2017 - Jan 2019

- Collaborated with design teams to create the front end template for a customer portal launched to 40,000
 active users using Salesforce Aura Components framework
- Acted as principal consultant for a client by planning future roadmaps, creating statements of work and supporting production issues

- Selectively chosen by Salesforce to present a 20 minute talk at Dreamforce 2018 about JavaScript testing on the Lightning Platform
- Developed a cross-browser, public facing Google Maps application that has logged an average of 8,000 unique searches a day

Technical Consultant Co-op

Apr 2016 - Aug 2016

- Published a Salesforce managed package written in JavaScript and Apex that improves developer productivity by providing dashboard versioning capabilities for the Wave Analytics application
- Supported the development and release of a custom Stripe payment subscription system built on Salesforce to a 300 person user base

Cardant, formerly Avanti Commerce

.NET Developer Co-op

May 2015 - Dec 2015

- Optimized an internal PDF exporting tool by converting it from a server to client side JavaScript application, achieving a 75% reduction in wait time
- Spearheaded the refactoring of an ASP.NET test suite following Agile methodology, resulting in a 20% increase in code coverage

Projects

React Library | react-brandywine-editor

Jan 2020

- Created an open source React-based block editor used for creating custom web blogging content
- Used Node.js tooling to automate build processes and package publishing to npm
- Implemented a plugin based design that allows other developers to easily add on to the application

React Application | alecng.ca/blog

Nov 2019

- Designed a portfolio and blogging platform using React and Firebase
- Created a custom CMS system that integrated a Firebase hosted NoSQL database with react-brandywineeditor to power a photo blog

Education

Bachelor of Applied Sciences, Computer Engineering, 2017 University of British Columbia Academic Distinction